###### Last Updated: July 30, 2024

Speedcheck Privacy Policy
=========================

Your privacy is very important to us. Accordingly, we have developed this Policy in order for you to understand how we collect, use, communicate and disclose and make use of personal information.

General Information
-------------------

* * *

Etrality GmbH ("us", "we", or "our") operates the https://www.speedcheck.org website and the Speedcheck mobile application (the "Service").

This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our Service and the choices you have associated with that data.

We use your data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy. Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms and Conditions.

For the purposes of this privacy policy, we are responsible for the processing of personal data. In particular, you can contact us by e-mail at info@etrality.com or by telephone at 004980355069056.

Definitions
-----------

* * *

### Personal Data

Personal Data means data about a living individual who can be identified from those data (or from those and other information either in our possession or likely to come into our possession).

### Usage Data

Usage Data is data collected automatically either generated by the use of the Service or from the Service infrastructure itself (for example, the duration of a page visit).

### Cookies

Cookies are small pieces of data stored on a User’s device.

### Data Controller

Data Controller means a person who (either alone or jointly or in common with other persons) determines the purposes for which and the manner in which any personal data are, or are to be, processed.

For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, we are a Data Controller of your data.

### Data Processor (or Service Providers)

Data Processor (or Service Provider) means any person (other than an employee of the Data Controller) who processes the data on behalf of the Data Controller.

We may use the services of various Service Providers in order to process your data more effectively.

### Data Subject

Data Subject is any living individual who is the subject of Personal Data.

### User

The User is the individual using our Service. The User corresponds to the Data Subject, who is the subject of Personal Data.

Information Collection And Use
------------------------------

* * *

We collect several different types of information for various purposes to provide and improve our Service to you.

### Types of Data Collected

#### Personal Data

While using our Service, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you ("Personal Data"). Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to:

* Email address
* First name and last name
* Cookies and Usage Data

We may use your Personal Data to contact you with newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. You may opt out of receiving any, or all, of these communications from us by following the unsubscribe link or instructions provided in any email we send or by contacting us.

#### Usage Data

We may also collect information that your browser sends whenever you visit our Service or when you access the Service by or through a mobile device ("Usage Data").

This Usage Data may include information such as your computer's Internet Protocol address (e.g. IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of our Service that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.

When you access the Service by or through a mobile device, this Usage Data may include information such as the type of mobile device you use, your mobile device unique ID, the IP address of your mobile device, your mobile operating system, the type of mobile Internet browser you use, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.

#### Location Data

We may use and store information about your location if you give us permission to do so (“Location Data”). We use this data to provide features of our Service, to improve and customize our Service.

You can enable or disable location services when you use our Service at any time, through your device settings.

#### Tracking & Cookies Data

We use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track the activity on our Service and hold certain information.

Cookies are files with small amount of data which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device. Tracking technologies also used are beacons, tags, and scripts to collect and track information and to improve and analyze our Service.

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Service.

Examples of Cookies we use:

* **Session Cookies.** We use Session Cookies to operate our Service.
* **Preference Cookies.** We use Preference Cookies to remember your preferences and various settings.
* **Security Cookies.** We use Security Cookies for security purposes.
* **Advertising Cookies.** Advertising Cookies are used to serve you with advertisements that may be relevant to you and your interests.

Data Details
------------

* * *

With Speedcheck we run a service that gives you the ability to test and analyze network and internet connections and monitor their performance based on the generated test results. We may use the results generated by you as the basis for our research and analysis business in which we provide network performance insights to our customers in a multitude of ways and formats. Speedcheck is currently available on iOS, Android as well as the Web. In addition, we license our technology to interested businesses in order for them to enable their customers to leverage our technology to perform internet performance tests.

Data we collect when you run a speed test with Speedcheck on any of your devices, on any platform or the web:

* Test Data: Metrics like ping, download and upload speed, amount of data transferred, test duration etc.
* Location Data: If a device supports precise location (based on GPS, mostly the case for smartphones) and you have granted access, we record precise device location. We also record non-precise location information based on the IP address a test is run from.
* Additional Metrics: We also collect additional points that are interesting in order to measure and analyze network and internet performance. These include but are not limited to the IP address you run a test from, the network operator (ISP) as well as device, network and hardware identifiers such as Wi-Fi names (SSID) or SIM card identifiers (IMEI)

If you have Speedcheck installed on your smartphone, tablet or other mobile devices and I’ve you have granted us the necessary permissions we also sporadically record precise location data with our apps running in the background to analyze network and internet performance.

We have identified the data collected, processed and analyzed by Speedcheck and provided to our business partners to be of legitimate interest to our business and are therefore able to process the data along with your user information on the legal basis of legitimate interests to operating our business.

In addition to the aforementioned data which is core to our business, we also generate additional revenue by collecting & sharing ad IDs and location data with selected 3rd parties that use the data to show you only relevant ads. We ask you for your explicit consent in order to do so.

Use of Data
-----------

* * *

Etrality GmbH uses the collected data for various purposes:

* To provide and maintain our Service
* To notify you about changes to our Service
* To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Service when you choose to do so
* To provide customer support
* To gather analysis or valuable information so that we can improve our Service
* To monitor the usage of our Service
* To detect, prevent and address technical issues
* To provide you with news, special offers and general information about other goods, services and events which we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about unless you have opted not to receive such information

Retention of Data
-----------------

* * *

Etrality GmbH will retain your Personal Data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We will retain and use your Personal Data to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your data to comply with applicable laws), resolve disputes, and enforce our legal agreements and policies.

Etrality GmbH will also retain Usage Data for internal analysis purposes. Usage Data is generally retained for a shorter period of time, except when this data is used to strengthen the security or to improve the functionality of our Service, or we are legally obligated to retain this data for longer time periods.

Transfer Of Data
----------------

* * *

Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.

If you are located outside Germany and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data, including Personal Data, to Germany and process it there.

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

Etrality GmbH will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.

Partnerships
------------

* * *

### CellRebel

This application uses CellRebel’s technology. CellRebel may sample data from your device, including location data, for the purposes of analyzing the following areas: network performance, network user experience and user equipment performance. This information can be shared with third parties in an aggregated format without personal identifiable information with the purpose to improve the network performance or to be used in designing marketing campaigns. Further information can be obtained in the Privacy Policy found at [www.cellrebel.com/privacy\_policy](https://www.speedcheck.org/privacy/www.cellrebel.com/privacy_policy).

### Cumberland Solutions S.L.

Cumberland Solutions S.L. ([Weplan Analytics](https://www.weplananalytics.com/)) is a crowdsourcing mobile data and analytics company focused on the telecommunications industry. Weplan Analytics collaborates with mobile operators, TowerCos and Telecommunications Regulatory Agencies in order to improve their network coverage through Business Intelligence Reports and Network Quality of Experience Dashboards.

Using this app and permitting Weplan Analytics to measure network performance linked with location data (from GPS or network-based location) in a pseudonymized manner, may help improve the performance of the networks you use. Weplan Analytics combines data collected from millions of devices, fully anonymizing data before providing their customers with network performance maps.

Weplan Analytics doesn't collect sensitive personal information like name, phone number or email, nor personal identifiers like Mobile Advertising ID, IMEI, IMSI or ICCID to ensure data is not attributed to particular and identifiable consumers.

To read more about what data is collected by Weplan Analytics and its privacy policy, please follow the [link](https://www.weplananalytics.com/en/sdk_disclaimer/privacy-policy).

### HUQ

To help us improve our service we collect the following information on an anonymous basis: Operating System, BluetoothName, Carrier Code (Android only), Carrier Name, Sim Code, Charging Status, Device Model, Device Manufacturer, Country, Locale, Bundle ID, Date & time, SSID (network), BSSID (network), Latitude, Longitude, Accuracy (GPS), Scanned networks. In addition to helping us to measure the usage of our app this anonymous information is shared with third parties for their business purposes, including the creation of reports, market research and trend analysis. One of these third parties is Huq, data shared does not contain information from which users can be identified and we will not provide additional information to such third parties that enables such third parties to identify you. You can find a full description of Huq and what it does with the information collected via our app [here](https://huq.io/privacy-policy?referrer=Etrality).

### OpenSignal

Opensignal collects data on mobile network coverage and performance. Opensignal uses the crowdsourced data collected from users’ devices to publish reports and metrics on mobile network experience. You can see Opensignal’s reports here: [https://www.opensignal.com/market-analysis](https://www.opensignal.com/market-analysis)

Opensignal is the independent global standard for measuring real-world mobile network experience. Opensignal believes that measuring how the network performs directly through users’ eyes is key to building better wireless networks.

To read more about the data collected by Opensignal and our privacy policy please follow the [link](https://opensignal.com/privacypolicy-for-crowdsourcedata).

### Outlogic

When this app is in use (or running in the background) we collect and share with our business partners the following device and location data: Precise location data of the device, WiFi signals or Bluetooth Low Energy devices in your proximity, device-based advertising identifiers, app names and/or identifiers, and information about your mobile device such as type of device, operating system version and type, device settings, time zone, carrier, and IP address.

* That data may be used for the following purposes: (a) to customize and measure ads in apps and other advertising; (b) for app and user analytics; (c) for disease prevention, and cybersecurity; (d) for market, civic / government or other research regarding aggregated human foot and traffic patterns, and (e) to generate proprietary pseudonymized identifiers tied to the information collected for the above purposes.
* The information we collect, including device data and identifiers and precise location data, may be shared with third parties including advertising and data companies, brands, and analytics, non-profit, financial, government and research organizations and other businesses that do location-based analytics (and their service providers).”
* To opt out of the use and sale of our partner Outlogic, a location data provider, please go to Outlogic’s “Your Privacy Choices” page at https://outlogic.io/opt-out-form/
* For GDPR, Outlogic’s Trusted Partner List: https://outlogic.io/trusted-partners/

For further information about Outlogic's data practices, please see Outlogic's [Privacy Policy](https://outlogic.io/privacy-policy/).

You may opt out of the above usage by declining data collection when when you start the app for the first time or in the setting toggle the switch for Enable Data Collection. If you want previous data to be forgotten send us an email.

### Ogury

We use Ogury's technology to provide users with a personalised advertising experience.

The information Ogury collects includes your device identifiers, location, email address, installed apps list and usage statistics, IP addresses (and in some cases URLs) contacted by your device and crash reports.

For further information about Ogury’s data practices, please see Ogury's [Privacy Policy](https://www.ogury.com/privacy-policy).

### SpeedChecker

If you consent to background data collection (your consent can be changed anytime in App Settings), then Speedchecker Ltd (“SpeedChecker”) will collect the following information:

* Your location (by GPS, cell or wi-fi geolocation methods).
* Information about connected wi-fi networks & neighbourhood networks: their configuration and signal strengths.
* Mobile network parameters such as connection type (2G, 3G, 4G, 5G), signal strength and other cellular network metrics.
* Device bandwidth usage.
* Internet measurements such as video streaming quality, throughput, latency, web page loading speed.
* Pseudonymized device identifier and IP address.

SpeedChecker may use the data collected above to calculate aggregated statistics relating to cellular networks and Internet quality in your area. The collected data can be shared with SpeedChecker clients to help them analyze network quality and performance.

The SpeedChecker SDK does not collect any sensitive personal information such as names, phone numbers or email addresses.

The SpeedChecker SDK collects pseudonymised device identifiers and IP addresses for the purposes of analytics and calculating how many unique users in our datasets are. Device IDs are not used to track people, identify any individuals, or display targeted advertising.

### Tutela Technologies Ltd.

We’ve partnered with Tutela to support the development of our app while respecting your privacy.

Tutela measures mobile network experience and does not collect any information that directly identifies you or your device. Tutela helps telecom ecosystem companies around the world better understand and improve network coverage and experience for mobile application users like you.

Tutela may collect data relating to wireless network performance, including: Geolocation data, identifiers (e.g. network names, cell tower IDs, BSSID, other access point information, and a randomly assigned Daily Session Tag that is reset every 24 hours and not linked to your identity), and app state. Tutela uses this data to gather information on network experience, for example by plotting network performance on a map to convey coverage, and this data is shared only within the telecoms ecosystem, and only for the purposes of understanding, communicating, and optimizing network performance, and in accordance with [Tutela's Privacy Charter](https://public.tutela.com/TutelaPrivacyCharter.pdf).

Using this app and permitting Tutela to collect this data may help improve the performance of your wireless network and your apps, and you have the right to opt-out of data sharing with Tutela at any time. To do so please use the opt-out measures provided in your mobile application or this privacy statement, or visit Tutela’s [Do Not Sell My Info](https://www.tutela.com/opt-out) webpage.

### umlaut communications GmbH

Umlaut is a global, full-service, cross-industry, end-to-end company that offers advisory and fulfilment services to clients all over the world.

Umlaut does only collect so-called pseudonymous data, the information that is not directly associated with the real-life identity of the user. NO Names, email addresses, phone numbers (MSISDN), SIM card info (IMSI), device ID (IMEI), Messages or Passwords are collected.

In addition to the results of the tests run in the app other localization information and technical (system) parameters are obtained. Some technical parameters (such as wireless network information) are collected periodically, e.g. subject to GPS localization events.

Specifically, the following data might be collected from the user's device and analyzed:

* Internet availability / success ratio
* Download time
* Latency (“ping”)
* Download speed
* Upload speed
* Dropped calls
* Wireless access technology
* Coverage / signal strength

The data collected is used statistically, with the purposes of supporting the development and improvement of communication networks. The data is totally anonymized and used from us to benchmark and optimize different Network Service Providers in the world.

In case of any clarification that you might need, you can contact anytime our Data Privacy Officer at the e-mail address ins.datenschutz@umlaut.com

Further details on umlaut privacy approach can be checked on this webpage: [https://tacs.c0nnectthed0ts.com/policy1/data\_privacy.html](https://tacs.c0nnectthed0ts.com/policy1/data_privacy.html)

### Placer Labs Inc.

Placer Labs Inc may collect and share precise location information, including the presence of connected devices via Bluetooth or Wi-Fi. The location data collected is stripped of identifiers such as device IDs, MAIDs, names, etc, on our cloud before it is sent to the partner. Placer Labs Inc. may use the data in aggregated or anonymized forms for market research purposes only.Placer Labs Inc may collect and share precise location information, including the presence of connected devices via Bluetooth or Wi-Fi. The location data collected is stripped of identifiers such as device IDs, MAIDs, names, etc, on our cloud before it is sent to the partner. Placer Labs Inc. may use the data in aggregated or anonymized forms for market research purposes only.

Further details on Placer's privacy approach can be checked on this webpage: [https://www.placer.ai/privacy-policy/consumer-privacy-policy](https://www.placer.ai/privacy-policy/consumer-privacy-policy)

Disclosure Of Data
------------------

* * *

### Business Transaction

If Etrality GmbH is involved in a merger, acquisition or asset sale, your Personal Data may be transferred. We will provide notice before your Personal Data is transferred and becomes subject to a different Privacy Policy.

### Disclosure for Law Enforcement

Under certain circumstances, Etrality GmbH may be required to disclose your Personal Data if required to do so by law or in response to valid requests by public authorities (e.g. a court or a government agency).

### Legal Requirements

Etrality GmbH may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:

* To comply with a legal obligation
* To protect and defend the rights or property of Etrality GmbH
* To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Service
* To protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the public
* To protect against legal liability

Security Of Data
----------------

* * *

The security of your data is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

"Do Not Track" Signals
----------------------

* * *

We do not support Do Not Track ("DNT"). Do Not Track is a preference you can set in your web browser to inform websites that you do not want to be tracked.

You can enable or disable Do Not Track by visiting the Preferences or Settings page of your web browser.

Your Rights
-----------

* * *

Etrality GmbH aims to take reasonable steps to allow you to correct, amend, delete, or limit the use of your Personal Data.

Whenever made possible, you can update your Personal Data directly within your account settings section. If you are unable to change your Personal Data, please contact us to make the required changes.

If you wish to be informed what Personal Data we hold about you and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact us.

In certain circumstances, you have the right:

* To access and receive a copy of the Personal Data we hold about you
* To rectify any Personal Data held about you that is inaccurate
* To request the deletion of Personal Data held about you

You have the right to data portability for the information you provide to Etrality GmbH. You can request to obtain a copy of your Personal Data in a commonly used electronic format so that you can manage and move it.

Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before responding to such requests.

Service Providers
-----------------

* * *

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service ("Service Providers"), to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.

These third parties have access to your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

### Analytics

We may use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyze the use of our Service.

* **Google Analytics**
    
    Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.
    
    For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: [http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)
    
* **Firebase**
    
    Firebase is analytics service provided by Google Inc.
    
    You may opt-out of certain Firebase features through your mobile device settings, such as your device advertising settings or by following the instructions provided by Google in their Privacy Policy: [http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)
    
    We also encourage you to review the Google's policy for safeguarding your data: [https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245). For more information on what type of information Firebase collects, please visit please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: [http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

### Advertising

We may use third-party Service Providers to show advertisements to you to help support and maintain our Service.

* **AdMob by Google**
    
    AdMob by Google is provided by Google Inc.
    
    You can opt-out from AdMob by Google service by following the instructions described by Google: [https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en)
    
    For more information on how Google uses the collected information, please visit the "How Google uses data when you use our partners' sites or app" page: [http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/) or visit the Privacy Policy of Google: [http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)
    
* **Adincube**
    
    Adincube is an advertising service provided by Ogury Ltd.
    
    For more information about Adincube, please visit their Privacy Policy: [https://storage.googleapis.com/adincube-resources/doc/Privacy\_policy.pdf](https://storage.googleapis.com/adincube-resources/doc/Privacy_policy.pdf)

### Payments

We may provide paid products and/or services within the Service. In that case, we use third-party services for payment processing (e.g. payment processors).

We will not store or collect your payment card details. That information is provided directly to our third-party payment processors whose use of your personal information is governed by their Privacy Policy. These payment processors adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands like Visa, Mastercard, American Express and Discover. PCI-DSS requirements help ensure the secure handling of payment information.

The payment processors we work with are:

* **Apple Store In-App Payments**
    
    Their Privacy Policy can be viewed at [https://www.apple.com/legal/privacy/en-ww/](https://www.apple.com/legal/privacy/en-ww/)
    
* **Google Play In-App Payments**
    
    Their Privacy Policy can be viewed at [https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)

Links To Other Sites
--------------------

* * *

Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party's site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.

We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.

Children's Privacy
------------------

* * *

Our Service does not address anyone under the age of 13 ("Children").

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Children has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

Changes
-------

* * *

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.

You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

Contact Us
----------

* * *

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us by email: info@etrality.com:

Trusted Partners
----------------

* * *

* ###### Products

* ###### Resources

* ###### About

* ###### Language
